import { QuestionGroup } from "~/global";

export const questionBank: QuestionGroup[] = [
  {
    lessonId: "1",
    title: "Lesson1 单数代词及a/an的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "我是一个男孩（boy）。",
        answer: "I am a boy."
      },
      {
        question: "你是一位老师（teacher）。",
        answer: "You are a teacher."
      },
      {
        question: "他是一个学生（student）。",
        answer: "He is a student."
      },
      {
        question: "她是一位医生（doctor）。",
        answer: "She is a doctor."
      },
      {
        question: "它是一本书（book）。",
        answer: "It is a book."
      },
      {
        question: "它是一条狗（dog）。",
        answer: "It is a dog."
      },
      {
        question: "这是一把椅子（chair）。",
        answer: "This is a chair."
      },
      {
        question: "那是一辆车（car）。",
        answer: "That is a car."
      },
      {
        question: "它是一个苹果（apple）。",
        answer: "It is an apple."
      },
      {
        question: "这个是一个苹果。",
        answer: "This is an apple."
      },
      {
        question: "那个是一个苹果。",
        answer: "That is an apple."
      },
      {
        question: "它是一架飞机（airplane）。",
        answer: "It is an airplane."
      },
      {
        question: "这个是一架飞机。",
        answer: "This is an airplane."
      },
      {
        question: "那个是一个架飞机。",
        answer: "That is an airplane."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "2",
    title: "Lesson2 复数代词及复数名词的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "我们是女孩。",
        answer: "We are girls."
      },
      {
        question: "我们是医生。",
        answer: "We are doctors."
      },
      {
        question: "你们是男孩。",
        answer: "You are boys."
      },
      {
        question: "你们是农夫。",
        answer: "You are farmers."
      },
      {
        question: "他们是学生。",
        answer: "They are students."
      },
      {
        question: "他们是小偷（thieves）。",
        answer: "They are thieves."
      },
      {
        question: "这些是狗。",
        answer: "These are dogs."
      },
      {
        question: "这些是猫。",
        answer: "These are cats."
      },
      {
        question: "那些是公交车。",
        answer: "Those are buses."
      },
      {
        question: "那些是小刀（knives）。",
        answer: "Those are knives."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "3",
    title: "Lesson3 形容词的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "你是一个矮的男孩。",
        answer: "You are a short boy."
      },
      {
        question: "我是一位高的老师。",
        answer: "I am a tall teacher."
      },
      {
        question: "他是一个胖的学生。",
        answer: "He is a fat student."
      },
      {
        question: "她是一位瘦的医生。",
        answer: "She is a thin doctor."
      },
      {
        question: "它是一本好书。",
        answer: "It is a good book."
      },
      {
        question: "它是一只聪明的狗。",
        answer: "It is a smart dog."
      },
      {
        question: "这是一把新的椅子。",
        answer: "This is a new chair."
      },
      {
        question: "那个是一辆大的汽车。",
        answer: "That is a big car."
      },
      {
        question: "它是一个苹果。",
        answer: "It is an apple."
      },
      {
        question: "这是一个小的苹果。",
        answer: "This is a small apple."
      },
      {
        question: "那是一个大的苹果。",
        answer: "That is a big apple."
      },
      {
        question: "它是一架飞机。",
        answer: "It is an airplane."
      },
      {
        question: "这是一架蓝色的飞机。",
        answer: "This is a blue airplane."
      },
      {
        question: "那是一架漂亮的飞机。",
        answer: "That is a beautiful airplane."
      },
      {
        question: "我们是快乐的女孩。",
        answer: "We are happy girls."
      },
      {
        question: "我们是忙碌的医生。",
        answer: "We are busy doctors."
      },
      {
        question: "你们是强壮的男孩。",
        answer: "You are strong boys."
      },
      {
        question: "你们是懒惰的农夫。",
        answer: "You are lazy farmers."
      },
      {
        question: "他们是愚笨的学生。",
        answer: "They are stupid students."
      },
      {
        question: "这些是肮脏的狗。",
        answer: "These are dirty dogs."
      },
      {
        question: "这些是干净的猫。",
        answer: "These are clean cats."
      },
      {
        question: "那些是白色的公交车。",
        answer: "Those are white buses."
      },
      {
        question: "那些是旧的小刀。",
        answer: "Those are old knives."
      },
      {
        question: "这个女孩是快乐的。",
        answer: "This girl is happy."
      },
      {
        question: "这个医生是忙碌的。",
        answer: "This doctor is busy."
      },
      {
        question: "那只狗是干净的。",
        answer: "That dog is clean."
      },
      {
        question: "那只猫是脏的。",
        answer: "That cat is dirty."
      },
      {
        question: "这些书是好的。",
        answer: "These books are good."
      },
      {
        question: "这些椅子是坏的。",
        answer: "These chairs are bad."
      },
      {
        question: "那些公交车是白色的。",
        answer: "Those buses are white."
      },
      {
        question: "那些树是绿色的。",
        answer: "Those trees are green."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "4",
    title: "Lesson4 一般疑问句的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "你是忙碌的。",
        answer: "You are busy."
      },
      {
        question: "你是忙碌的吗？",
        answer: "Are you busy?"
      },
      {
        question: "她是矮的。",
        answer: "She is short."
      },
      {
        question: "她是矮的吗？",
        answer: "Is she short?"
      },
      {
        question: "我是高的。",
        answer: "I am tall."
      },
      {
        question: "我是高的吗?",
        answer: "Am I tall?"
      },
      {
        question: "这是一本书。",
        answer: "This is a book."
      },
      {
        question: "这是一本书吗？",
        answer: "Is this a book?"
      },
      {
        question: "他是一个高个子男孩。",
        answer: "He is a tall boy."
      },
      {
        question: "他是一个高个子男孩吗？",
        answer: "Is he a tall boy?"
      },
      {
        question: "他是一位聪明的老师。",
        answer: "He is a smart teacher."
      },
      {
        question: "他是一个聪明的老师吗？",
        answer: "Is he a smart teacher?"
      },
      {
        question: "那是只好狗。",
        answer: "That is a good dog."
      },
      {
        question: "那是只好狗吗？",
        answer: "Is that a good dog?"
      },
      {
        question: "这只狗是聪明的。",
        answer: "This dog is smart."
      },
      {
        question: "这只狗是聪明的吗？",
        answer: "Is this dog smart?"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "5",
    title: "Lesson5 Yes的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "这是一本好书。",
        answer: "This is a good book."
      },
      {
        question: "这是一本好书吗？",
        answer: "Is this a good book?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，它是。",
        answer: "Yes, it is."
      },
      {
        question: "是的，它是一本好书。",
        answer: "Yes, it is a good book."
      },
      {
        question: "那只狗是聪明的。",
        answer: "That dog is smart."
      },
      {
        question: "那只狗是聪明的吗？",
        answer: "Is that dog smart?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，它是。",
        answer: "Yes, it is."
      },
      {
        question: "是的，它是聪明的。",
        answer: "Yes, it is smart."
      },
      {
        question: "她是一位好医生。",
        answer: "She is a good doctor."
      },
      {
        question: "她是一位好医生吗？",
        answer: "Is she a good doctor?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，她是。",
        answer: "Yes, she is."
      },
      {
        question: "是的，她是一位好医生。",
        answer: "Yes, she is a good doctor."
      },
      {
        question: "那位医生是忙碌的。",
        answer: "That doctor is busy."
      },
      {
        question: "那位医生是忙碌的吗？",
        answer: "Is that doctor busy?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，他是。",
        answer: "Yes, he is."
      },
      {
        question: "是的，他是忙碌的。",
        answer: "Yes, he is busy."
      },
      {
        question: "那位高的老师是胖的。",
        answer: "That tall teacher is fat."
      },
      {
        question: "那位高的老师是胖的吗？",
        answer: "Is that tall teacher fat?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，他是的。",
        answer: "Yes, he is."
      },
      {
        question: "是的，他是胖的。",
        answer: "Yes, he is fat."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "6",
    title: "Lesson6 No的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "你是快乐的。",
        answer: "You are happy."
      },
      {
        question: "你不是快乐的。",
        answer: "You are not happy."
      },
      {
        question: "那张书桌是小的。",
        answer: "That desk is small."
      },
      {
        question: "那张书桌不是小的。",
        answer: "That desk is not small."
      },
      {
        question: "你是胖的。",
        answer: "You are fat."
      },
      {
        question: "你是胖的吗？",
        answer: "Are you fat?"
      },
      {
        question: "不，我不是胖的。",
        answer: "No, I am not fat."
      },
      {
        question: "这只狗是脏的。",
        answer: "This dog is dirty."
      },
      {
        question: "这只狗是脏的吗？",
        answer: "Is this dog dirty?"
      },
      {
        question: "不，它不是脏的。",
        answer: "No, it is not dirty."
      },
      {
        question: "那个妈妈是瘦的。",
        answer: "That mother is thin."
      },
      {
        question: "那个妈妈是瘦的吗？",
        answer: "Is that mother thin?"
      },
      {
        question: "不，那个妈妈不是瘦的。",
        answer: "No, that mother is not thin."
      },
      {
        question: "这些书是新的。",
        answer: "These books are new."
      },
      {
        question: "这些书是新的吗？",
        answer: "Are these books new?"
      },
      {
        question: "不，这些书不是新的。",
        answer: "No, these books are not new."
      },
      {
        question: "那些学生是聪明的。",
        answer: "Those students are smart."
      },
      {
        question: "那些学生是聪明的吗？",
        answer: "Are those students smart?"
      },
      {
        question: "不，那些学生不是聪明的。",
        answer: "No, those students are not smart."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "7",
    title: "Lesson7 人称代词的所有格用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "它是我的餐桌。",
        answer: "It is my table."
      },
      {
        question: "它是我的餐桌吗？",
        answer: "Is it my table?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，它是我的餐桌。",
        answer: "Yes, it is my table."
      },
      {
        question: "我是你的老师。",
        answer: "I am your teacher."
      },
      {
        question: "我是你的老师吗？",
        answer: "Am I your teacher?"
      },
      {
        question: "不，你不是我的老师。",
        answer: "No, you are not my teacher."
      },
      {
        question: "那是他的房子。",
        answer: "That is his house."
      },
      {
        question: "那是他的房子吗？",
        answer: "Is that his house?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，那是他的房子。",
        answer: "Yes, that is his house."
      },
      {
        question: "那是她的书桌。",
        answer: "That is her desk."
      },
      {
        question: "那是她的书桌吗？",
        answer: "Is that her desk?"
      },
      {
        question: "不，那不是她的书桌。",
        answer: "No, that is not her desk."
      },
      {
        question: "那是我们的书桌。",
        answer: "That is our desk."
      },
      {
        question: "那是我们的书桌吗?",
        answer: "Is that our desk?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，那是我们的书桌。",
        answer: "Yes, that is our desk."
      },
      {
        question: "这是他们的狗。",
        answer: "This is their dog."
      },
      {
        question: "这是他们的狗吗？",
        answer: "Is this their dog?"
      },
      {
        question: "不，这个不是他们的狗。",
        answer: "No, this is not their dog."
      },
      {
        question: "这些是你们的椅子。",
        answer: "These are your chairs."
      },
      {
        question: "这些是你们的椅子吗？",
        answer: "Are these your chairs?"
      },
      {
        question: "不，这些不是我们的椅子。",
        answer: "No, these are not our chairs."
      },
      {
        question: "那些是我们的朋友。",
        answer: "Those are our friends."
      },
      {
        question: "那些是我们的朋友吗？",
        answer: "Are those our friends?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，那些是我们的朋友。",
        answer: "Yes, those are our friends."
      },
      {
        question: "我的学生是高的。",
        answer: "My student is tall."
      },
      {
        question: "我的学生是高的吗？",
        answer: "Is my student tall?"
      },
      {
        question: "你的老师是矮的。",
        answer: "Your teacher is short."
      },
      {
        question: "你的老师是矮的吗？",
        answer: "Is your teacher short?"
      },
      {
        question: "他的爸爸是快乐的。",
        answer: "His father is happy."
      },
      {
        question: "他的爸爸是快乐的吗？",
        answer: "Is his father happy?"
      },
      {
        question: "她的妹妹们是伤心的。",
        answer: "Her sisters are sad."
      },
      {
        question: "她的妹妹们是伤心的吗？",
        answer: "Are her sisters sad?"
      },
      {
        question: "它的耳朵是红色的。",
        answer: "Its ear is red."
      },
      {
        question: "它的耳朵是红色的吗？",
        answer: "Is its ear red?"
      },
      {
        question: "我们的医生是忙碌的",
        answer: "Our doctor is busy."
      },
      {
        question: "我们的医生是忙碌的吗？",
        answer: "Is our doctor busy?"
      },
      {
        question: "你们的钢琴(piano)是白色的。",
        answer: "Your piano is white."
      },
      {
        question: "你们的钢琴是白色的吗？",
        answer: "Is your piano white?"
      },
      {
        question: "他们的司机是懒惰的。",
        answer: "Their driver is lazy."
      },
      {
        question: "他们的司机是懒惰的吗？",
        answer: "Is their driver lazy?"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "8",
    title: "Lesson8 What疑问句与专有名词",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "这个是什么？",
        answer: "What is this?"
      },
      {
        question: "这是一本书。",
        answer: "This is a book."
      },
      {
        question: "那个是什么？",
        answer: "What is that?"
      },
      {
        question: "那是一只笔。",
        answer: "That is a pen."
      },
      {
        question: "这是你的名字。",
        answer: "This is your name."
      },
      {
        question: "这是你的名字吗？",
        answer: "Is this your name?"
      },
      {
        question: "你的名字是什么？",
        answer: "What is your name?"
      },
      {
        question: "那是他的名字。",
        answer: "That is his name."
      },
      {
        question: "那是他的名字吗？",
        answer: "Is that his name?"
      },
      {
        question: "他的名字是什么？",
        answer: "What is his name?"
      },
      {
        question: "什么是你的名字？",
        answer: "What is your name?"
      },
      {
        question: "我的名字是Jason。",
        answer: "My name is Jason."
      },
      {
        question: "什么是她的名字?",
        answer: "What is her name?"
      },
      {
        question: "她的名字是玛丽。",
        answer: "Her name is Mary."
      },
      {
        question: "什么是他的名字？",
        answer: "What is his name?"
      },
      {
        question: "他的名字是比利。",
        answer: "His name is Billy."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "9",
    title: "Lesson9 Why疑问句的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "他的猫是脏的。",
        answer: "His cat is dirty."
      },
      {
        question: "他的猫是脏的吗？",
        answer: "Is his cat dirty?"
      },
      {
        question: "为什么他的猫是脏的？",
        answer: "Why is his cat dirty?"
      },
      {
        question: "那张桌子是小的。",
        answer: "That table is small."
      },
      {
        question: "那张桌子是小的吗？",
        answer: "Is that table small?"
      },
      {
        question: "为什么那张桌子是小的？",
        answer: "Why is that table small?"
      },
      {
        question: "你的哥哥是生病的。",
        answer: "Your brother is sick."
      },
      {
        question: "你的哥哥是生病的吗？",
        answer: "Is your brother sick?"
      },
      {
        question: "为什么你的哥哥是生病的？",
        answer: "Why is your brother sick?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个学生是笨的。",
        answer: "That student is stupid."
      },
      {
        question: "那个学生是笨的吗？",
        answer: "Is that student stupid?"
      },
      {
        question: "为什么那个学生是笨的？",
        answer: "Why is that student stupid?"
      },
      {
        question: "你的叔叔是自私的。",
        answer: "Your uncle is selfish."
      },
      {
        question: "你的叔叔是自私的吗？",
        answer: "Is your uncle selfish?"
      },
      {
        question: "为什么你的叔叔是自私的？",
        answer: "Why is your uncle selfish?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个邮差是诚实的。",
        answer: "That postman is honest."
      },
      {
        question: "那个邮差是诚实的吗？",
        answer: "Is that postman honest?"
      },
      {
        question: "为什么那个邮差是诚实的？",
        answer: "Why is that postman honest?"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "10",
    title: "Lesson10 Every的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "每一栋房子都是绿色的。",
        answer: "Every house is green."
      },
      {
        question: "每一栋房子都是绿色的吗？",
        answer: "Is every house green?"
      },
      {
        question: "为什么每一栋房子都是绿色的？",
        answer: "Why is every house green?"
      },
      {
        question: "每一位邮差都是忙碌的",
        answer: "Every postman is busy."
      },
      {
        question: "每一位邮差都是忙碌的吗？",
        answer: "Is every postman busy?"
      },
      {
        question: "为什么每一位邮差都是忙碌的？",
        answer: "Why is every postman busy?"
      },
      {
        question: "每一只猫都是干净的。",
        answer: "Every cat is clean."
      },
      {
        question: "每一只猫都是干净的吗？",
        answer: "Is every cat clean?"
      },
      {
        question: "为什么每一只猫都是干净的",
        answer: "Why is every cat clean?"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "11",
    title: "Lesson11 连词 because 的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "那个农夫是瘦的。",
        answer: "That farmer is thin."
      },
      {
        question: "那个农夫是瘦的吗？",
        answer: "Is that farmer thin?"
      },
      {
        question: "为什么那个农夫是瘦的？",
        answer: "Why is that farmer thin?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个农夫是瘦的因为他是生病的。",
        answer: "That farmer is thin because he is sick."
      },
      {
        question: "你是虚弱(weak)的。",
        answer: "You are weak."
      },
      {
        question: "你是虚弱的吗？",
        answer: "Are you weak?"
      },
      {
        question: "为什么你是虚弱的？",
        answer: "Why are you weak?"
      },
      {
        question: "我虚弱的是因为我生病的。",
        answer: "I am weak because I am sick."
      },
      {
        question: "这个名字是好的。",
        answer: "This name is good."
      },
      {
        question: "这个名字是好的吗？",
        answer: "Is this name good?"
      },
      {
        question: "为什么这个名字是好的？",
        answer: "Why is this name good?"
      },
      {
        question: "这个名字是好的因为它是我的名字。",
        answer: "This name is good because it is my name."
      },
      {
        question: "戴维是一个好学生。",
        answer: "David is a good student."
      },
      {
        question: "为什么戴维是个好学生？",
        answer: "Why is David a good student?"
      },
      {
        question: "戴维是个好学生因为他是诚实的。",
        answer: "David is a good student because he is honest."
      },
      {
        question: "他是一位好医生。",
        answer: "He is a good doctor."
      },
      {
        question: "他是一位好医生吗？",
        answer: "Is he a good doctor?"
      },
      {
        question: "为什么他是一位好医生？",
        answer: "Why is he a good doctor?"
      },
      {
        question: "他是一位好医生因为他是仁慈的。",
        answer: "He is a good doctor because he is kind."
      },
      {
        question: "我的学生们是聪明的。",
        answer: "My students are smart."
      },
      {
        question: "我的学生们是聪明的吗？",
        answer: "Are my students smart?"
      },
      {
        question: "为什么我的学生们是聪明的？",
        answer: "Why are my students smart?"
      },
      {
        question: "因为你是聪明的，你的学生们是聪明的。",
        answer: "Because you are smart, your students are smart."
      },
      {
        question: "这张书桌是好的。",
        answer: "This desk is good."
      },
      {
        question: "这张书桌是好的吗？",
        answer: "Is this desk good?"
      },
      {
        question: "为什么这张书桌是好的？",
        answer: "Why is this desk good?"
      },
      {
        question: "因为这张书桌是干净的，它是好的。",
        answer: "Because this desk is clean, it is good."
      },
      {
        question: "我哥哥是伤心的。",
        answer: "My brother is sad."
      },
      {
        question: "我的哥哥是伤心的吗？",
        answer: "Is my brother sad?"
      },
      {
        question: "为什么我哥哥是伤心的？",
        answer: "Why is my brother sad?"
      },
      {
        question: "因为你哥哥是生病的，他是伤心的。",
        answer: "Because your brother is sick, he is sad."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "12",
    title: "Lesson12 Who疑问句的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "那个邮差是谁？",
        answer: "Who is that postman?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个邮差是我父亲。",
        answer: "That postman is my father."
      },
      {
        question: "那个司机是谁？",
        answer: "Who is that driver?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个司机是我叔叔。",
        answer: "That driver is my uncle."
      },
      {
        question: "那个学生是谁？",
        answer: "Who is that student?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个学生是杰森。",
        answer: "That student is Jason."
      },
      {
        question: "这个女孩是谁？",
        answer: "Who is this girl?"
      },
      {
        question: "这个女孩是我的朋友。",
        answer: "This girl is my friend."
      },
      {
        question: "你的护士是谁？",
        answer: "Who is your nurse?"
      },
      {
        question: "我的护士是那个女孩。",
        answer: "My nurse is that girl."
      },
      {
        question: "那个男服务生是谁？",
        answer: "Who is that waiter?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个男服务生是我的哥哥。",
        answer: "That waiter is my brother."
      },
      {
        question: "那个女服务生是谁？",
        answer: "Who is that waitress?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个女服务生是我的姐姐。",
        answer: "That waitress is my sister."
      },
      {
        question: "你的弟弟是谁？",
        answer: "Who is your brother?"
      },
      {
        question: "我的弟弟是比利。",
        answer: "My brother is Billy."
      },
      {
        question: "你的朋友是谁？",
        answer: "Who is your friend?"
      },
      {
        question: "我的朋友是林先生。",
        answer: "My friend is Mr. Lin."
      },
      {
        question: "他的祖母是谁？",
        answer: "Who is his grandmother?"
      },
      {
        question: "他的祖母是林太太。",
        answer: "His grandmother is Mrs. Lin."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "13",
    title: "Lesson13 How疑问句与fine 的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "那个邮差身体好吗？",
        answer: "How is that postman?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个邮差身体很好。",
        answer: "That postman is fine."
      },
      {
        question: "那个婴儿身体好吗？",
        answer: "How is that baby?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个婴儿很好。",
        answer: "That baby is fine."
      },
      {
        question: "你的朋友身体好吗？",
        answer: "How is your friend?"
      },
      {
        question: "我的朋友很好。",
        answer: "My friend is fine."
      },
      {
        question: "那个司机身体好吗？",
        answer: "How is that driver?"
      },
      {
        question: "他很好。",
        answer: "He is fine."
      },
      {
        question: "她的叔叔身体好吗？",
        answer: "How is her uncle?"
      },
      {
        question: "他很好。",
        answer: "He is fine."
      },
      {
        question: "玛丽身体好吗？",
        answer: "How is Mary?"
      },
      {
        question: "她很好。",
        answer: "She is fine."
      },
      {
        question: "你是多高呢？",
        answer: "How tall are you?"
      },
      {
        question: "我妈妈是多生气呢？",
        answer: "How angry is my mother?"
      },
      {
        question: "他的祖母是多大年纪呢？",
        answer: "How old is his grandmother?"
      },
      {
        question: "你的学生是多诚实呢？",
        answer: "How honest is your student?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个邮差是有多忙碌呢?",
        answer: "How busy is that postman?"
      },
      {
        question: "我们的老师是多伤心呢？",
        answer: "How sad is our teacher?"
      },
      {
        question: "那只狗是有多大呢？",
        answer: "How big is that dog?"
      },
      {
        question: "那架飞机是多漂亮呢？",
        answer: "How beautiful is that airplane?"
      },
      {
        question: "我儿子是多笨呢？",
        answer: "How stupid is my son?"
      },
      {
        question: "你女儿是有多懒惰呢？",
        answer: "How lazy is your daughter?"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "14",
    title: "Lesson14 Where疑问句的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "玛丽在哪里？",
        answer: "Where is Mary?"
      },
      {
        question: "你在哪里？",
        answer: "Where are you?"
      },
      {
        question: "他们在哪里？",
        answer: "Where are they?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个医生在哪里?",
        answer: "Where is that doctor?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个男服务生在哪里？",
        answer: "Where is that waiter?"
      },
      {
        question: "她的父母在哪里？",
        answer: "Where are her parents?"
      },
      {
        question: "我的朋友们在哪里？",
        answer: "Where are my friends?"
      },
      {
        question: "你的时钟在哪里？",
        answer: "Where is your clock?"
      },
      {
        question: "我的杯子在哪里？",
        answer: "Where is my cup?"
      },
      {
        question: "她的沙发(sofa)在哪里？",
        answer: "Where is her sofa?"
      },
      {
        question: "那家商店在哪里？",
        answer: "Where is that store?"
      },
      {
        question: "那家书店是在哪里？",
        answer: "Where is that bookstore?"
      },
      {
        question: "我的脚踏车在哪里？",
        answer: "Where is my bicycle?"
      },
      {
        question: "我们的学校在哪里？",
        answer: "Where is our school?"
      },
      {
        question: "他们的教室在哪里？",
        answer: "Where is their classroom?"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "15",
    title: "Lesson15 介词in的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "你妹妹在哪里？",
        answer: "Where is your sister?"
      },
      {
        question: "我妹妹是在她的房间里。",
        answer: "My sister is in her room."
      },
      {
        question: "你妹妹是在她的房间里吗？",
        answer: "Is your sister in her room?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，她在。",
        answer: "Yes, she is."
      },
      {
        question: "为什么你妹妹是在她的房间里？",
        answer: "Why is your sister in her room?"
      },
      {
        question: "她在她的房间里因为她是疲倦的。",
        answer: "She is in her room because she is tired."
      },
      {
        question: "那个人在哪里？",
        answer: "Where is that person?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个人是在我的房子里。",
        answer: "That person is in my house."
      },
      {
        question: "那个人是在你的房子里吗？",
        answer: "Is that person in your house?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，他在。",
        answer: "Yes, he is."
      },
      {
        question: "为什么那个人是在你的房子里？",
        answer: "Why is that person in your house?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个人在我的房子里因为他是我的丈夫（husband）。",
        answer: "That person is in my house because he is my husband."
      },
      {
        question: "你的父亲在哪里？",
        answer: "Where is your father?"
      },
      {
        question: "我的父亲在他的办公室里。",
        answer: "My father is in his office."
      },
      {
        question: "你的父亲在他的办公室吗？",
        answer: "Is your father in his office?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，他在。",
        answer: "Yes, he is."
      },
      {
        question: "为什么你的父亲在他的办公室？",
        answer: "Why is your father in his office?"
      },
      {
        question: "他在他的办公室因为他是忙碌的.",
        answer: "He is in his office because he is busy."
      },
      {
        question: "那位友善的（friendly）女服务生在哪里？",
        answer: "Where is that friendly waitress?"
      },
      {
        question: "那位友善的（friendly）女服务生在那家书店里。",
        answer: "That friendly waitress is in that bookstore."
      },
      {
        question: "那位友善的（friendly）女服务生在那家书店里吗？",
        answer: "Is that friendly waitress in that bookstore?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，她在。",
        answer: "Yes, she is."
      },
      {
        question: "为什么那位友善的（friendly）女服务生在那家书店里？",
        answer: "Why is that friendly waitress in that bookstore?"
      },
      {
        question: "她在那家书店里因为她的儿子在那家书店里。",
        answer: "She is in that bookstore because her son is in that bookstore."
      },
      {
        question: "那个健康的婴儿在哪里？",
        answer: "Where is that healthy baby?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个健康的婴儿在她的汽车里。",
        answer: "That healthy baby is in her car."
      },
      {
        question: "那个健康的婴儿在她的汽车里吗？",
        answer: "Is that healthy baby in her car?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，他在。",
        answer: "Yes, he is."
      },
      {
        question: "为什么那个健康的婴儿在她的汽车里？",
        answer: "Why is that healthy baby in her car?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个婴儿在她的汽车里因为她是他的母亲。",
        answer: "That baby is in her car because she is his mother."
      },
      {
        question: "那只猴子在哪里？",
        answer: "Where is that monkey?"
      },
      {
        question: "那只猴子在我的教室里。",
        answer: "That monkey is in my classroom."
      },
      {
        question: "那只猴子在你的教室里吗？",
        answer: "Is that monkey in your classroom?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，它在。",
        answer: "Yes, it is."
      },
      {
        question: "为什么那只猴子在你的教室里？",
        answer: "Why is that monkey in your classroom?"
      },
      {
        question: "它在我的教室里因为它是我的宠物",
        answer: "It is in my classroom because it is my pet."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "16",
    title: "Lesson16 介词on的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "那本书是在你的书桌上。",
        answer: "That book is on your desk."
      },
      {
        question: "那本书是在我的书桌上吗？",
        answer: "Is that book on my desk?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，它在。",
        answer: "Yes, it is."
      },
      {
        question: "为什么那本书在我的书桌上？",
        answer: "Why is that book on my desk?"
      },
      {
        question: "那本书在你的桌子上因为它是你的书。",
        answer: "That book is on your desk because it is your book."
      },
      {
        question: "那只狗是在她的餐桌上。",
        answer: "That dog is on her table."
      },
      {
        question: "那只狗是在她的餐桌上吗？",
        answer: "Is that dog on her table?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，它在。",
        answer: "Yes, it is."
      },
      {
        question: "为什么那只狗是在她的餐桌上？",
        answer: "Why is that dog on her table?"
      },
      {
        question: "那只狗在她的餐桌上因为它是饿的。",
        answer: "That dog is on her table because it is hungry."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "17",
    title: "Lesson17 其他常用介词",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "那把钥匙是在那个盒子里。",
        answer: "That key is in that box."
      },
      {
        question: "那把钥匙是在那个盒子吗？",
        answer: "Is that key in that box?"
      },
      {
        question: "不，它不在。",
        answer: "No, it is not."
      },
      {
        question: "那把钥匙在你的桌上。",
        answer: "That key is on your table."
      },
      {
        question: "她的狗是在那个商店旁边（at）。",
        answer: "Her dog is at that store."
      },
      {
        question: "她的狗是在那个商店旁边吗？",
        answer: "Is her dog at that store?"
      },
      {
        question: "不，它不在。",
        answer: "No, it is not."
      },
      {
        question: "她的狗是在你的丈夫旁边（beside）。",
        answer: "Her dog is beside your husband."
      },
      {
        question: "你的房子是在这个公园旁边（beside）。",
        answer: "Your house is beside this park."
      },
      {
        question: "你的房子是在这个公园旁边吗？",
        answer: "Is your house beside this park?"
      },
      {
        question: "不，我的房子不是在这个公园旁边。",
        answer: "No, my house is not beside this park."
      },
      {
        question: "我的房子是在这个公园附近（near）。",
        answer: "My house is near this park."
      },
      {
        question: "那个气球是在这颗树下（below）。",
        answer: "That balloon is below this tree."
      },
      {
        question: "那个气球是在这颗树下吗?",
        answer: "Is that balloon below this tree?"
      },
      {
        question: "不，它不在。",
        answer: "No, it is not."
      },
      {
        question: "那个气球在这颗树的上方（above）。",
        answer: "That balloon is above this tree."
      },
      {
        question: "那只蝴蝶（butterfly）在他的头正上方（over）。",
        answer: "That butterfly is over his head."
      },
      {
        question: "那只蝴蝶在他的头正上方吗？",
        answer: "Is that butterfly over his head?"
      },
      {
        question: "不，它不在。",
        answer: "No, it is not."
      },
      {
        question: "那只蝴蝶在那张桌子的正下方（under）。",
        answer: "That butterfly is under that desk."
      },
      {
        question: "那只鸟在那颗树上（in）。",
        answer: "That bird is in that tree."
      },
      {
        question: "那只鸟在那颗树上吗？",
        answer: "Is that bird in that tree?"
      },
      {
        question: "不，它不在。",
        answer: "No, it is not."
      },
      {
        question: "那只鸟在那个窗户旁边(beside)。",
        answer: "That bird is beside that window."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "18",
    title: "Lesson18 Whose疑问句的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "那本书是谁的？",
        answer: "Whose book is that?"
      },
      {
        question: "这本书是谁的？",
        answer: "Whose book is this?"
      },
      {
        question: "你是谁的老师？",
        answer: "Whose teacher are you?"
      },
      {
        question: "他是谁的父亲？",
        answer: "Whose father is he?"
      },
      {
        question: "这些鸟是谁的？",
        answer: "Whose birds are these?"
      },
      {
        question: "这些鸡是谁的？",
        answer: "Whose chickens are these?"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "19",
    title: "Lesson19 单、复数名词的所有格表达",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "杰森的房间是小的。",
        answer: "Jason's room is small."
      },
      {
        question: "你学生的狗是大的。",
        answer: "Your student's dog is big."
      },
      {
        question: "那只猫的尾巴（tail）是短的。",
        answer: "That cat's tail is short."
      },
      {
        question: "他是我妹妹的朋友。",
        answer: "He is my sister's friend."
      },
      {
        question: "这个人是玛丽的司机。",
        answer: "This person is Mary's driver."
      },
      {
        question: "那些猫的尾巴是白色的。",
        answer: "Those cats' tails are white."
      },
      {
        question: "这些是我的老师的书。",
        answer: "These are my teachers' books."
      },
      {
        question: "那些是我的弟弟们的房间。",
        answer: "Those are my brothers' rooms."
      },
      {
        question: "这些小孩的手是干净的。",
        answer: "These children's hands are clean."
      },
      {
        question: "那些女人们的帽子是漂亮的。",
        answer: "Those women's hats are beautiful."
      },
      {
        question: "那些男人们的车是脏的。",
        answer: "Those men's cars are dirty."
      },
      {
        question: "那本书是谁的？",
        answer: "Whose book is that?"
      },
      {
        question: "那本书是她的。",
        answer: "That book is hers."
      },
      {
        question: "这本书是谁的？",
        answer: "Whose book is this?"
      },
      {
        question: "这本书是我的。",
        answer: "This book is mine."
      },
      {
        question: "这只狗是谁的？",
        answer: "Whose dog is this?"
      },
      {
        question: "这只狗是你的。",
        answer: "This dog is yours."
      },
      {
        question: "那只猫是谁的？",
        answer: "Whose cat is that?"
      },
      {
        question: "那只猫是他们的。",
        answer: "That cat is theirs."
      },
      {
        question: "这些鸡是谁的?",
        answer: "Whose chickens are these?"
      },
      {
        question: "这些鸡是他的。",
        answer: "These chickens are his."
      },
      {
        question: "那些书是谁的?",
        answer: "Whose books are those?"
      },
      {
        question: "那些书是我们的。",
        answer: "Those books are ours."
      },
      {
        question: "这些花是谁的?",
        answer: "Whose flowers are these?"
      },
      {
        question: "这些花是你们的。",
        answer: "These flowers are yours."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "20",
    title: "Lesson20 Which疑问句的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "哪一颗树是我们的树？",
        answer: "Which is our tree?"
      },
      {
        question: "哪一个是你的小孩？",
        answer: "Which is your child?"
      },
      {
        question: "哪一个是他的苹果？",
        answer: "Which is his apple?"
      },
      {
        question: "哪一些是她的椅子？",
        answer: "Which are her chairs?"
      },
      {
        question: "哪一些是你们的宠物？",
        answer: "Which are your pets?"
      },
      {
        question: "哪一些是他们的钥匙？",
        answer: "Which are their keys?"
      },
      {
        question: "哪一本书是你的？",
        answer: "Which book is yours?"
      },
      {
        question: "哪一张椅子是他们的？",
        answer: "Which chair is theirs?"
      },
      {
        question: "哪一只蝴蝶是漂亮的？",
        answer: "Which butterfly is beautiful?"
      },
      {
        question: "哪一只猴子是在那颗树下？",
        answer: "Which monkey is under that tree?"
      },
      {
        question: "哪一些女孩是友善的？",
        answer: "Which girls are friendly?"
      },
      {
        question: "哪一些老师是生气的？",
        answer: "Which teachers are angry?"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "21",
    title: "Lesson21 定冠词the的用法及无生命的所有格",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "那个学生是贫穷的。",
        answer: "The student is poor."
      },
      {
        question: "这个医生是富有的。",
        answer: "The doctor is rich."
      },
      {
        question: "那只狗是虚弱的。",
        answer: "The dog is weak."
      },
      {
        question: "那些护士是有耐心（patient）的。",
        answer: "The nurses are patient."
      },
      {
        question: "这些人是错误的。",
        answer: "The persons are wrong."
      },
      {
        question: "篮子（basket）的把手（handle）是好的。",
        answer: "The handle of basket is good."
      },
      {
        question: "戒指（ring）的钻石（diamond）是漂亮的。",
        answer: "The diamond of ring is beautiful."
      },
      {
        question: "教室的墙壁是脏的。",
        answer: "The walls of classroom are dirty."
      },
      {
        question: "杯子(cup)的盖子(cap)是黑色的。",
        answer: "The cap of cup is black."
      },
      {
        question: "句子（sentence）中的单词（word）是错误的。",
        answer: "The word of sentence is wrong."
      },
      {
        question: "房间的钥匙是错的",
        answer: "The key of room is wrong."
      },
      {
        question: "毛巾（towel）上的污点（spot）是绿色的",
        answer: "The spot of towel is green."
      },
      {
        question: "表上的玻璃是新的。",
        answer: "The glass of watch is new."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "22",
    title: "Lesson22 连词but，and，or的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "那个杯子是新的，但它是脏的。",
        answer: "The cup is new, but it is dirty."
      },
      {
        question: "我的收音机是旧的，但它是好的。",
        answer: "My radio is old, but it is good."
      },
      {
        question: "那个男服务生是穷的，但他是亲切的(kind)。",
        answer: "The waiter is poor, but he is kind."
      },
      {
        question: "那个医生是富有的，但他是自私的。",
        answer: "The doctor is rich, but he is selfish."
      },
      {
        question: "这个花园是小的，但它是漂亮的。",
        answer: "The garden is small, but it is beautiful."
      },
      {
        question: "那个年轻人是有胖又脏的。",
        answer: "The young person is fat and dirty."
      },
      {
        question: "这只狗是又干净又聪明的。",
        answer: "The dog is clean and smart."
      },
      {
        question: "我们的父母是又生气又伤心的。",
        answer: "Our parents are angry and sad."
      },
      {
        question: "玛丽和杰森是好学生。",
        answer: "Mary and Jason are good students."
      },
      {
        question: "你妈妈和我姑姑（aunt）是女服务生。",
        answer: "Your mother and my aunt are waitresses."
      },
      {
        question: "这只猫和那只狗是懒惰的。",
        answer: "The cat and the dog are lazy."
      },
      {
        question: "他们的卧室和厨房（kitchen）是脏的。",
        answer: "Their bedroom and kitchen is dirty."
      },
      {
        question: "你的房间是小的而且你的房间是脏的。",
        answer: "Your room is small and your room is dirty."
      },
      {
        question: "我的狗是大的而且我的狗是聪明的。",
        answer: "My dog is big and my dog is smart."
      },
      {
        question: "那些小孩是干净的还是脏的呢？",
        answer: "Are those children clean or dirty?"
      },
      {
        question: "那些是我们的或他们的笔呢？",
        answer: "Are those pens ours or theirs?"
      },
      {
        question: "这间卧室是我们的还是他们的？",
        answer: "Is this bedroom ours or theirs?"
      },
      {
        question: "这个手表是新的或是旧的？",
        answer: "Is this watch new or old?"
      },
      {
        question: "那间教室是大的还是小的呢？",
        answer: "Is that classroom large or small?"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "23",
    title: "Lesson23 连词although及so用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "虽然这架钢琴是好的，它是旧的",
        answer: "Although the piano is good, it is old."
      },
      {
        question: "虽然我的哥哥是聪明的，他是自私的",
        answer: "Although my brother is smart, he is selfish."
      },
      {
        question: "虽然那个新邮差是笨的，他是体贴（nice）的。",
        answer: "Although the new postman is stupid, he is nice."
      },
      {
        question: "虽然那个司机是健康的，他是瘦的。",
        answer: "Although the driver is healthy, he is thin."
      },
      {
        question: "这架钢琴是好的虽然它是旧的",
        answer: "The piano is good although it is old."
      },
      {
        question: "我的哥哥是自私的的虽然他是聪明的",
        answer: "My brother is selfish although he is smart."
      },
      {
        question: "那个新邮差是体贴的虽然他是笨的。",
        answer: "The new postman is nice although he is stupid."
      },
      {
        question: "那个司机是瘦的虽然他是健康的。",
        answer: "The driver is thin although he is healthy."
      },
      {
        question: "他是健康的，所以他是快乐的。",
        answer: "He is healthy, so he is happy."
      },
      {
        question: "她是生病的，所以她是疲倦的。",
        answer: "She is sick, so she is tired."
      },
      {
        question: "这个手表是好的，所以它是昂贵（expensive）的。",
        answer: "The watch is good, so it is expensive."
      },
      {
        question: "那架钢琴是旧的，所以它是便宜的。",
        answer: "The piano is old, so it is cheap."
      },
      {
        question: "那条狗是生病的，所以它是虚弱的。",
        answer: "The dog is sick, so it is weak."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "24",
    title: "Lesson24 There be 的用法与数字的写法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "有一只鸟在你的桌上。",
        answer: "There is a bird on your desk."
      },
      {
        question: "有一只鸟在你的桌上吗？",
        answer: "Is there a bird on your desk?"
      },
      {
        question: "有一只猫在我们的桌上。",
        answer: "There is a cat on our table."
      },
      {
        question: "有一只猫在我们的桌上吗？",
        answer: "Is there a cat on our table?"
      },
      {
        question: "有一只狗在你的卧室里。",
        answer: "There is a dog in your bedroom."
      },
      {
        question: "有一只狗在你的卧室里吗？",
        answer: "Is there a dog in your bedroom?"
      },
      {
        question: "有一个年轻人在你的房子里。",
        answer: "There is a young person in your house."
      },
      {
        question: "有一个年轻人在你的房子里吗？",
        answer: "Is there a young person in your house?"
      },
      {
        question: "有一个婴儿在他们的房间里。",
        answer: "There is a baby in their room."
      },
      {
        question: "有一个婴儿在他们的房间里吗？",
        answer: "Is there a baby in their room?"
      },
      {
        question: "有3本书在你的书桌上。",
        answer: "There are three books on your desk."
      },
      {
        question: "有3本书在你的书桌上吗？",
        answer: "Are there three books on your desk?"
      },
      {
        question: "有16只猫在我们的餐桌上。",
        answer: "There are sixteen cats on our table."
      },
      {
        question: "有16只猫在我们的餐桌上吗？",
        answer: "Are there sixteen cats on our table?"
      },
      {
        question: "有47个年轻人在你的房子里。",
        answer: "There are forty-seven young persons in your house."
      },
      {
        question: "有47个年轻人在你的房子里吗？",
        answer: "Are there forty-seven young persons in your house?"
      },
      {
        question: "有89个鸡蛋在他们的厨房里。",
        answer: "There are eighty-nine eggs in their kitchen."
      },
      {
        question: "有89个鸡蛋在他们的厨房里吗？",
        answer: "Are there eighty-nine eggs in their kitchen?"
      },
      {
        question: "有115只狗在你的花园里。",
        answer: "There are one-hundred and fifteen dogs in your garden."
      },
      {
        question: "有115只狗在你的花园里吗？",
        answer: "Are there one-hundred and fifteen dogs in your garden?"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "25",
    title: "Lesson25 动词have的用法及三大人称",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "我有一艘旧船（boat）。",
        answer: "I have an old boat."
      },
      {
        question: "有一艘旧船在车库（garage）里。",
        answer: "There is an old boat in the garage."
      },
      {
        question: "你有一把新刀。",
        answer: "You have a new knife."
      },
      {
        question: "有一把新刀在桌子下（under）。",
        answer: "There is a new knife under the table."
      },
      {
        question: "他有一条红色的领带（tie）。",
        answer: "He has a red tie."
      },
      {
        question: "有一条红色的领带在椅子上。",
        answer: "There is a red tie on the chair."
      },
      {
        question: "她有两块漂亮的手表。",
        answer: "She has two beautiful watches."
      },
      {
        question: "有两块漂亮的手表在厨房里。",
        answer: "There are two beautiful watches in the kitchen."
      },
      {
        question: "那个男孩有3个气球。",
        answer: "The boy has three balloons."
      },
      {
        question: "有3个气球在房子上面（above）。",
        answer: "There are three balloons above the house."
      },
      {
        question: "这个女孩有4条蓝色的裙子。",
        answer: "The girl has four blue skirts."
      },
      {
        question: "有4条蓝色的裙子在客厅里（living room）。",
        answer: "There are four blue skirts in the living room."
      },
      {
        question: "他们有11只老虎。",
        answer: "They have eleven tigers."
      },
      {
        question: "有11只老虎在动物园里。",
        answer: "There are eleven tigers in the zoo."
      },
      {
        question: "我们有45只大象。",
        answer: "We have forty-five elephants."
      },
      {
        question: "有45只大象在（at）车站。",
        answer: "There are forty-five elephants at the station."
      },
      {
        question: "那些人有119辆公交车。",
        answer: "The people have one-hundred and nineteen buses."
      },
      {
        question: "有119辆公交车在工厂（factory）里。",
        answer: "There are one-hundred and nineteen buses in the factory."
      },
      {
        question: "这些小孩有4把新的雨伞(umbrella)。",
        answer: "The children have four new umbrellas."
      },
      {
        question: "有4把新雨伞在窗户旁边",
        answer: "There are four new umbrellas beside the window."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "26",
    title: "Lesson26 动词teach的用法、主格和宾格",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "我教你英文。",
        answer: "I teach you English."
      },
      {
        question: "你教我英文。",
        answer: "You teach me English."
      },
      {
        question: "他教他英文。",
        answer: "He teaches him English."
      },
      {
        question: "她教她数学（math）。",
        answer: "She teaches her math."
      },
      {
        question: "他教她数学。",
        answer: "He teaches her math."
      },
      {
        question: "我教你们历史（history）。",
        answer: "I teach you history."
      },
      {
        question: "他们教我们历史。",
        answer: "They teach us history."
      },
      {
        question: "你的老师教我们艺术（art）。",
        answer: "Your teacher teaches us art."
      },
      {
        question: "我的妈妈教你艺术。",
        answer: "My mother teaches you art."
      },
      {
        question: "她的姐姐教他们艺术。",
        answer: "Her sister teaches them art."
      },
      {
        question: "你们的医生教我音乐。",
        answer: "Your doctor teaches me music."
      },
      {
        question: "我们的老师教他们音乐。",
        answer: "Our teacher teaches them music."
      },
      {
        question: "他们的爸爸教我们音乐。",
        answer: "Their father teaches us music."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "27",
    title: "Lesson27 助动词Do和Does的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "我教你英文。",
        answer: "I teach you English."
      },
      {
        question: "我教你英文吗？",
        answer: "Do I teach you English?"
      },
      {
        question: "你教我英文。",
        answer: "You teach me English."
      },
      {
        question: "你教我英文吗？",
        answer: "Do you teach me English?"
      },
      {
        question: "他教他英文。",
        answer: "He teaches him English."
      },
      {
        question: "他教他英文吗？",
        answer: "Does he teach him English?"
      },
      {
        question: "她教他数学。",
        answer: "She teaches him math."
      },
      {
        question: "她教他数学吗？",
        answer: "Does she teach him math?"
      },
      {
        question: "她教她数学。",
        answer: "She teaches her math."
      },
      {
        question: "她教她数学吗？",
        answer: "Does she teach her math?"
      },
      {
        question: "他教她数学。",
        answer: "He teaches her math."
      },
      {
        question: "他教她数学吗？",
        answer: "Does he teach her math?"
      },
      {
        question: "我教你历史。",
        answer: "I teach you history."
      },
      {
        question: "我教你历史吗？",
        answer: "Do I teach you history?"
      },
      {
        question: "他们教我们历史。",
        answer: "They teach us history."
      },
      {
        question: "他们教我们历史？",
        answer: "Do they teach us history?"
      },
      {
        question: "我们教他们历史。",
        answer: "We teach them history."
      },
      {
        question: "我们教他们历史吗？",
        answer: "Do we teach them history?"
      },
      {
        question: "你的老师教我们美术。",
        answer: "Your teacher teaches us art."
      },
      {
        question: "你的老师教我们美术吗？",
        answer: "Does your teacher teach us art?"
      },
      {
        question: "我妈妈教你们美术。",
        answer: "My mother teaches you art."
      },
      {
        question: "我妈妈教你们美术吗？",
        answer: "Does my mother teach you art?"
      },
      {
        question: "她姐姐教他们美术。",
        answer: "Her sister teaches them art."
      },
      {
        question: "她姐姐教他们美术吗？",
        answer: "Does her sister teach them art?"
      },
      {
        question: "你的医生教我音乐。",
        answer: "Your doctor teaches me music."
      },
      {
        question: "你的医生教我音乐吗？",
        answer: "Does your doctor teach me music?"
      },
      {
        question: "我们的老师教他们音乐。",
        answer: "Our teacher teaches them music."
      },
      {
        question: "我们的老师教他们音乐吗？",
        answer: "Does our teacher teach them music?"
      },
      {
        question: "他们的爸爸教我们音乐。",
        answer: "Their father teaches us music."
      },
      {
        question: "他们的爸爸教我们音乐吗？",
        answer: "Does their father teach us music?"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "28",
    title: "Lesson28 肯定回答的表达",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "我教你英文。",
        answer: "I teach you English."
      },
      {
        question: "我教你英文吗？",
        answer: "Do I teach you English?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，你教。",
        answer: "Yes, you do."
      },
      {
        question: "你教我英文。",
        answer: "You teach me English."
      },
      {
        question: "你教我英文吗？",
        answer: "Do you teach me English?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，我教。",
        answer: "Yes, I do."
      },
      {
        question: "他教她英文。",
        answer: "He teaches her English."
      },
      {
        question: "他教她英文吗？",
        answer: "Does he teach her English?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，他教。",
        answer: "Yes, he does."
      },
      {
        question: "她教他数学。",
        answer: "She teaches him math."
      },
      {
        question: "她教他数学吗？",
        answer: "Does she teach him math?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，她教。",
        answer: "Yes, she does."
      },
      {
        question: "他们教我们历史。",
        answer: "They teach us history."
      },
      {
        question: "他们教我们历史吗？",
        answer: "Do they teach us history?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，他们教。",
        answer: "Yes, they do."
      },
      {
        question: "我们教他们历史。",
        answer: "We teach them history."
      },
      {
        question: "我们教他们历史吗？",
        answer: "Do we teach them history?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，我们教。",
        answer: "Yes, we do."
      },
      {
        question: "你们教他们历史。",
        answer: "You teach them history."
      },
      {
        question: "你们教他们历史吗？",
        answer: "Do you teach them history?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，我们教。",
        answer: "Yes, we do."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "29",
    title: "Lesson29 否定句don't/doesn't的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "你有一条狗吗？",
        answer: "Do you have a dog?"
      },
      {
        question: "不，我没有。",
        answer: "No, I don't."
      },
      {
        question: "我没有一条狗",
        answer: "I don't have a dog."
      },
      {
        question: "他有一只笔吗？",
        answer: "Does he have a pen?"
      },
      {
        question: "不，他没有。",
        answer: "No, he doesn't."
      },
      {
        question: "他没有一只笔。",
        answer: "He doesn't have a pen."
      },
      {
        question: "他教我们英文吗？",
        answer: "Does he teach us English?"
      },
      {
        question: "不，他没有。",
        answer: "No, he doesn't."
      },
      {
        question: "他没有教我们英文。",
        answer: "He doesn't teach us English."
      },
      {
        question: "你爸爸教我们数学吗？",
        answer: "Does your father teach us math?"
      },
      {
        question: "不，他没有。",
        answer: "No, he doesn't."
      },
      {
        question: "他没有教我们数学。",
        answer: "He doesn't teach us math."
      },
      {
        question: "他们教你美术吗？",
        answer: "Do they teach you art?"
      },
      {
        question: "不，他们没有。",
        answer: "No, they don't."
      },
      {
        question: "他们没有教我美术。",
        answer: "They don't teach me art."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "30",
    title: "Lesson30 形容词many/much的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "我有许多鸟。",
        answer: "I have many birds."
      },
      {
        question: "有许多鸟在树上。",
        answer: "There are many birds in the tree."
      },
      {
        question: "他有许多书。",
        answer: "He has many books."
      },
      {
        question: "有许多书在我房间里。",
        answer: "There are many books in my room."
      },
      {
        question: "你有许多椅子。",
        answer: "You have many chairs."
      },
      {
        question: "有许多椅子在树下。",
        answer: "There are many chairs under the tree."
      },
      {
        question: "我们有许多猴子。",
        answer: "We have many monkeys."
      },
      {
        question: "有许多猴子在动物园里。",
        answer: "There are many monkeys in the zoo."
      },
      {
        question: "你们有许多学生。",
        answer: "You have many students."
      },
      {
        question: "有许多学生在教室里。",
        answer: "There are many students in the classroom."
      },
      {
        question: "时间是金钱。",
        answer: "Time is money."
      },
      {
        question: "他有许多钱。",
        answer: "He has much money."
      },
      {
        question: "有许多钱在我的房子里。",
        answer: "There is much money in my house."
      },
      {
        question: "我喝许多牛奶。",
        answer: "I drink much milk."
      },
      {
        question: "有许多水在水池里（pool）。",
        answer: "There is much water in the pool."
      },
      {
        question: "有许多啤酒（beer）在厨房里。",
        answer: "There is much beer in the kitchen."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "31",
    title: "Lesson31 疑问词及连词When的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "他何时教我英文？",
        answer: "When does he teach me English?"
      },
      {
        question: "你何时教她英文？",
        answer: "When do you teach her English?"
      },
      {
        question: "他何时教我们英文？",
        answer: "When does he teach us English?"
      },
      {
        question: "你有什么东西？",
        answer: "What do you have?"
      },
      {
        question: "他有什么东西？",
        answer: "What does he have?"
      },
      {
        question: "你在哪里教他？",
        answer: "Where do you teach him?"
      },
      {
        question: "他在哪里教你们？",
        answer: "Where does he teach you?"
      },
      {
        question: "为什么你教我们英文？",
        answer: "Why do you teach us English?"
      },
      {
        question: "为什么我教他们英文？",
        answer: "Why do I teach them English?"
      },
      {
        question: "他如何教我历史？",
        answer: "How does he teach me history?"
      },
      {
        question: "你们如何教她历史？",
        answer: "How do you teach her history?"
      },
      {
        question: "当他是忙碌的，他是生气的。",
        answer: "When he is busy, he is angry."
      },
      {
        question: "当那只鸟在树上，它是快乐的。",
        answer: "When that bird in the tree, it is happy."
      },
      {
        question: "当那只猴子在我的花园玩，它是快乐的。",
        answer: "When that monkey plays in my garden, it is happy."
      },
      {
        question: "当李先生教玛丽英文，她是快乐的。",
        answer: "When Mr.Lee teaches Mary English, she is happy."
      },
      {
        question: "他是生气的当他是忙碌的。",
        answer: "He is angry when he is busy."
      },
      {
        question: "那只鸟是快乐的当它在树上。",
        answer: "The bird is happy when it is in the tree."
      },
      {
        question: "这只猴子是快乐的当它在我的花园里玩。",
        answer: "The monkey is happy when it plays in my garden."
      },
      {
        question: "玛丽是开心的当李先生教她英文。",
        answer: "Mary is happy when Mr.Lee teaches her English."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "32",
    title: "Lesson32 疑问词How的其他用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "有多少学生在你的学校里？",
        answer: "How many students are there in your school?"
      },
      {
        question: "有93个学生在我的学校里。",
        answer: "There are ninety-three students in my school."
      },
      {
        question: "你教多少学生？",
        answer: "How many students do you teach?"
      },
      {
        question: "我教27个学生。",
        answer: "I teach twenty-seven students."
      },
      {
        question: "她教多少学生？",
        answer: "How many students does she teach?"
      },
      {
        question: "她教31个学生。",
        answer: "She teaches thirty-one students."
      },
      {
        question: "有多少啤酒在汽车里？",
        answer: "How much beer is there in the car?"
      },
      {
        question: "我不知道。",
        answer: "I don't know."
      },
      {
        question: "你喝多少啤酒？",
        answer: "How much beer do you drink?"
      },
      {
        question: "他喝多少啤酒？",
        answer: "How much beer does he drink?"
      },
      {
        question: "你有多少钱？",
        answer: "How much money do you have?"
      },
      {
        question: "他有多少钱？",
        answer: "How much money does he have?"
      },
      {
        question: "我不知道因为我是醉的（drunken）。",
        answer: "I don't know because I am drunken."
      },
      {
        question: "你多久一次教他们音乐？",
        answer: "How often do you teach them music?"
      },
      {
        question: "你的妈妈多久教你一次？",
        answer: "How often does your mother teach you?"
      },
      {
        question: "你多久一次教他们数学？",
        answer: "How often do you teach them math?"
      },
      {
        question: "她多久一次教我们美术？",
        answer: "How often does she teach us art?"
      },
      {
        question: "他们多久一次喝酒？",
        answer: "How often do they drink?"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "33",
    title: "Lesson33 及物动词与不及物动词",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "我喜欢那辆蓝色的公交车",
        answer: "I like that blue bus."
      },
      {
        question: "你喜欢那辆蓝色的公交车吗？",
        answer: "Do you like that blue bus?"
      },
      {
        question: "是的，我喜欢。",
        answer: "Yes, I like it."
      },
      {
        question: "为什么你喜欢那辆蓝色的公交车？",
        answer: "Why do you like that blue bus?"
      },
      {
        question: "我喜欢那辆蓝色的公交车因为它是漂亮的。",
        answer: "I like that blue bus because it is beautiful."
      },
      {
        question: "我喜欢那个花园。",
        answer: "I like that garden."
      },
      {
        question: "你喜欢那个花园吗？",
        answer: "Do you like that garden?"
      },
      {
        question: "我喜欢那个花园因为有许多花在那个花园里。",
        answer: "I like that garden because there are many flowers in that garden."
      },
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "34",
    title: "Lesson34 动词不定式的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "我喜欢散步。",
        answer: "I like to walk."
      },
      {
        question: "我喜欢在那个公园里散步。",
        answer: "I like to walk in the park."
      },
      {
        question: "他喜欢跑步。",
        answer: "He likes to run."
      },
      {
        question: "他喜欢在这个森林（forest）里跑步。",
        answer: "He likes to run in the forest."
      },
      {
        question: "她喜欢游泳。",
        answer: "She likes to swim."
      },
      {
        question: "她喜欢在那个泳池里游泳。",
        answer: "She likes to swim in that pool."
      },
      {
        question: "他们喜欢玩耍。",
        answer: "They like to play."
      },
      {
        question: "他们喜欢在我的学校里玩耍。",
        answer: "They like to play in my school."
      },
      {
        question: "杰森的父亲喜欢教我们英文。",
        answer: "Jason's father likes to teach us English."
      },
      {
        question: "杰森的父亲喜欢在他的客厅里教我们英文。",
        answer: "Jason's father likes to teach us English in his living room."
      },
      {
        question: "他喜欢散步而且他喜欢游泳。",
        answer: "He likes to walk and he likes to swim."
      },
      {
        question: "他喜欢散步和游泳。",
        answer: "He likes to walk and swim."
      },
      {
        question: "我喜欢唱歌而且我喜欢开车。",
        answer: "I like to sing and I like to drive."
      },
      {
        question: "我喜欢唱歌和开车。",
        answer: "I like to sing and drive."
      },
      {
        question: "你喜欢学习（learn）而且你喜欢工作。",
        answer: "You like to learn and you like to work."
      },
      {
        question: "你喜欢学习和工作。",
        answer: "You like to learn and work."
      },
      {
        question: "那些猫喜欢吃而且那些猫喜欢睡。",
        answer: "Those cats like to eat and those cats like to sleep."
      },
      {
        question: "那些猫喜欢吃和睡。",
        answer: "Those cats like to eat and sleep."
      },
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "35",
    title: "Lesson35 频率副词的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "她的房子总是脏的。",
        answer: "Her house is always dirty."
      },
      {
        question: "她的钢琴常常是脏的。",
        answer: "Her piano is often dirty."
      },
      {
        question: "这个年轻人通常是虚弱。",
        answer: "The young person is usually weak."
      },
      {
        question: "那个邮差有时候是忙碌的。",
        answer: "The postman is sometimes busy."
      },
      {
        question: "他们的父母很少是仁慈的。",
        answer: "Their parents are seldom kind."
      },
      {
        question: "虽然那位绅士（gentleman）是富有的，他从不懒惰的。",
        answer: "Although that gentleman is rich, he is never lazy."
      },
      {
        question: "他们经常伤心的因为他们是常常生病的。",
        answer: "They are usually sad because they are often sick."
      },
      {
        question: "他女儿总是在房间里玩。",
        answer: "His daughter always plays in the room."
      },
      {
        question: "玛丽从不微笑。",
        answer: "Mary never smiles."
      },
      {
        question: "我妈妈很少在客厅里喝酒。",
        answer: "My mother seldom drinks in the living room."
      },
      {
        question: "那个老师经常在办公室里画画。",
        answer: "That teacher usually draws in the office."
      },
      {
        question: "你父亲有时候在这个泳池游泳。",
        answer: "Your father sometimes swims in the pool."
      },
      {
        question: "他常常教我英文。",
        answer: "He often teaches me English."
      },
      {
        question: "那个学生有时是懒惰的。",
        answer: "That student is sometimes lazy."
      },
      {
        question: "有时那个学生是懒惰的。",
        answer: "Sometimes that student is lazy."
      },
      {
        question: "那个老师有时候教我们英文。",
        answer: "That teacher sometimes teaches us English."
      },
      {
        question: "有时那个老师教我们英文。",
        answer: "Sometimes that teacher teaches us English."
      },
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "36",
    title: "Lesson36 方式副词的构成方式和用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "你妹妹跑得快。",
        answer: "Your sister runs quickly."
      },
      {
        question: "你妹妹跑得快吗？",
        answer: "Does your sister run quickly?"
      },
      {
        question: "我哥哥走的慢。",
        answer: "My brother walks slowly."
      },
      {
        question: "我哥哥走得慢吗？",
        answer: "Does my brother walk slowly?"
      },
      {
        question: "她伤心地唱歌。",
        answer: "She sings sadly."
      },
      {
        question: "她伤心地唱歌吗？",
        answer: "Does she sing sadly?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个女孩打扮得很漂亮。",
        answer: "That girl dresses beautifully."
      },
      {
        question: "那个女孩打扮得很漂亮吗？",
        answer: "Does that girl dress beautifully?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个学生快乐地学习。",
        answer: "That student learns happily."
      },
      {
        question: "那个学生快乐地学习吗？",
        answer: "Does that student learn happily?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个老人饥饿地工作。",
        answer: "That old man works hungrily."
      },
      {
        question: "那个老人饥饿地工作吗？",
        answer: "Does that old man work hungrily?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个司机忙碌地开车。",
        answer: "That driver drives busily."
      },
      {
        question: "那个司机忙碌地开车吗？",
        answer: "Does that driver drive busily?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个女孩生气地哭泣。",
        answer: "That girl cries angrily."
      },
      {
        question: "那个女孩生气地哭泣吗？",
        answer: "Does that girl cry angrily?"
      },
      {
        question: "那只鸟飞得快。",
        answer: "That bird flies fast."
      },
      {
        question: "为什么那只鸟飞得快？",
        answer: "Why does that bird fly fast?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个农夫早工作。",
        answer: "That farmer works early."
      },
      {
        question: "为什么那个农夫早工作？",
        answer: "Why does that farmer work early?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个男孩晚到达（arrive）。",
        answer: "That boy arrives late."
      },
      {
        question: "为什么那个男孩晚到达（arrive）？",
        answer: "Why does that boy arrive late?"
      },
      {
        question: "你朋友努力地工作。",
        answer: "Your friend works hard."
      },
      {
        question: "为什么你朋友努力地工作？",
        answer: "Why does your friend work hard?"
      },
      {
        question: "我妹妹唱得好。",
        answer: "My sister sings well."
      },
      {
        question: "为什么我妹妹唱得好？",
        answer: "Why does my sister sing well?"
      },
      {
        question: "那个老师英文教得好。",
        answer: "That teacher teaches English well."
      },
      {
        question: "为什么那个老师英文教得好？",
        answer: "Why does that teacher teach English well?"
      },
      {
        question: "这个学生画得差。",
        answer: "The student draws badly."
      },
      {
        question: "为什么这个学生画得差？",
        answer: "Why does the student draw badly?"
      },
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "37",
    title: "Lesson37 地点副词及时间副词的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "她常常来这里。",
        answer: "She often comes here."
      },
      {
        question: "她常常来这里吗？",
        answer: "Does she often come here?"
      },
      {
        question: "为什么她常常来这里？",
        answer: "Why does she often come here?"
      },
      {
        question: "她常常来这里因为她喜欢这里。",
        answer: "She often comes here because she likes it here."
      },
      {
        question: "他总是去那里。",
        answer: "He always goes there."
      },
      {
        question: "他总是去那里吗？",
        answer: "Does he always go there?"
      },
      {
        question: "他总是去那里因为他不喜欢来这里。",
        answer: "He always goes there because he doesn't like to come here."
      },
      {
        question: "我们今天学英文。",
        answer: "We learn English today."
      },
      {
        question: "我们今天学英文吗？",
        answer: "Do we learn English today?"
      },
      {
        question: "我们今天何时学英文？",
        answer: "When do we learn English today?"
      },
      {
        question: "我们今晚唱歌。",
        answer: "We sing tonight."
      },
      {
        question: "我们今晚唱歌吗？",
        answer: "Do we sing tonight?"
      },
      {
        question: "我们今晚何时唱歌？",
        answer: "When do we sing tonight?"
      },
      {
        question: "他现在是虚弱的。",
        answer: "He is weak now."
      },
      {
        question: "他现在是虚弱的吗？",
        answer: "Is he weak now?"
      },
      {
        question: "为什么他现在是虚弱的？",
        answer: "Why is he weak now?"
      },
      {
        question: "他来得早。",
        answer: "He comes early."
      },
      {
        question: "他来得早吗？",
        answer: "Does he come early?"
      },
      {
        question: "为什么他来得早？",
        answer: "Why does he come early?"
      },
      {
        question: "她来得晚。",
        answer: "She comes late."
      },
      {
        question: "她来得晚吗？",
        answer: "Does she come late?"
      },
      {
        question: "为什么她来得晚？",
        answer: "Why does she come late?"
      },
      {
        question: "我们今晚在这里唱歌。",
        answer: "We sing here tonight."
      },
      {
        question: "我们今天在那里学英文。",
        answer: "We learn English there today."
      },
      {
        question: "她现在在这里。",
        answer: "She is here now."
      },
      {
        question: "他早去那里。",
        answer: "He goes there early."
      },
      {
        question: "她晚来这里。",
        answer: "She comes here late."
      },
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "38",
    title: "Lesson38 程度副词的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "这架钢琴是非常好的，但它很旧。",
        answer: "This piano is very good, but it is very old."
      },
      {
        question: "我的哥哥是非常聪明的，但他很自私。",
        answer: "My brother is very smart, but he is selfish."
      },
      {
        question: "那个农夫是非常笨的，但他很体贴。",
        answer: "That farmer is very stupid, but he is nice."
      },
      {
        question: "虽然这只狗非常小，它跑得很快。",
        answer: "Although the dog is very small, it runs very fast."
      },
      {
        question: "那个学生是非常聪明的，因为他学得很快。",
        answer: "That student is very smart because he learns very quickly."
      },
      {
        question: "我非常喜欢那个女孩，因为她很可爱。",
        answer: "I like the girl very much because she is very cute."
      },
      {
        question: "我非常喜欢那只鸟，因为它唱得很好。",
        answer: "I like that bird very much because it sings very well."
      },
      {
        question: "我的妈妈也是非常生气。",
        answer: "My mother is also very angry."
      },
      {
        question: "你的妈妈也是非常生气的吗？",
        answer: "Is your mother very angry too?"
      },
      {
        question: "他也有一台收音机。",
        answer: "He also has a radio."
      },
      {
        question: "他也有一台收音机吗？",
        answer: "Does he have a radio too?"
      },
      {
        question: "我也喜欢在这里唱歌。",
        answer: "I also like to sing here."
      },
      {
        question: "你也喜欢在这里唱歌吗？",
        answer: "Do you like to sing here too?"
      },
      {
        question: "我也在那里教美术。",
        answer: "I also teach art there."
      },
      {
        question: "你也在那里教美术吗？",
        answer: "Do you teach art there too?"
      },
      {
        question: "我姐姐也不喜欢看电视。",
        answer: "My sister doesn't like to watch TV either."
      },
      {
        question: "他们也不喜欢在那个公园玩。",
        answer: "They don't like to play in the park either."
      },
      {
        question: "有多少鸟在我的书桌上？",
        answer: "How many birds are there on my desk?"
      },
      {
        question: "大约有10只鸟在你的书桌上。",
        answer: "There are about ten birds on your desk."
      },
      {
        question: "你有多少手表？",
        answer: "How many watches do you have?"
      },
      {
        question: "我大约有7块手表。",
        answer: "I have about seven watches."
      },
      {
        question: "有多少学生在那个学校？",
        answer: "How many students are there in the school?"
      },
      {
        question: "大约有360个学生在那个学校。",
        answer: "There are about three hundred and sixty students in that school."
      },
      {
        question: "你教多少学生？",
        answer: "How many students do you teach?"
      },
      {
        question: "我在那里教大约40个学生。",
        answer: "I teach about forty students there."
      },
      {
        question: "今天教室里只有3个人。",
        answer: "There are only three persons in the classroom today."
      },
      {
        question: "这里现在只有两小孩。",
        answer: "There are only two children here now."
      },
      {
        question: "我只有一个棒球（baseball）。",
        answer: "I only have a baseball."
      },
      {
        question: "他只喜欢在大海（ocean）里游泳。",
        answer: "He only likes to swim in the ocean."
      },
      {
        question: "这个小孩现在只想要那个玩具。",
        answer: "The child only wants that toy now."
      },
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "39",
    title: "Lesson39 常和动词搭配的介词to/with/for",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "那些狗常跑向公园。",
        answer: "Those dogs often run to the park."
      },
      {
        question: "为什么那些狗常跑向公园？",
        answer: "Why do those dogs often run to the park?"
      },
      {
        question:"它们常跑向公园因为它们喜欢那里。",
        answer: "They often run to the park because they like it there."
      },
      {
        question:"我常常去车站。",
        answer: "I often go to the station."
      },
      {
        question:"为什你常常去车站？",
        answer: "Why do you often go to the station?"
      },
      {
        question:"我常去车站因为我的母亲在那里工作。",
        answer: "I often go to the station because my mother works there."
      },
      {
        question:"那个胖司机很少来我的餐厅（restaurant）。",
        answer: "That fat driver seldom comes to my restaurant."
      },
      {
        question:"为什么那个胖司机很少去你的餐厅（restaurant）？",
        answer: "Why does that fat driver seldom go to your restaurant?"
      },
      {
        question:"他很少来我的餐厅因为我的餐厅是非常小的。",
        answer: "He seldom comes to my restaurant because my restaurant is very small."
      },
      {
        question:"那个医生经常很晚回家。",
        answer: "That doctor usually goes home late."
      },
      {
        question:"我的弟弟总是很早上床睡觉。",
        answer: "My brother always goes to bad early."
      },
      {
        question:"那个学生总是很早上学。",
        answer: "That student always goes to school early."
      },
      {
        question:"我经常和他游泳。",
        answer: "I often swim with him."
      },
      {
        question:"为什么你经常和他游泳？",
        answer: "Why do you often swim with him?"
      },
      {
        question:"因为他游得非常快，我想要学习他的技巧（skill）。",
        answer: "Because he swims very quickly, I want to learn his skill."
      },
      {
        question:"我很少和他喝酒。",
        answer: "I seldom drink with him."
      },
      {
        question:"为什么你很少和他喝酒？",
        answer: "Why do you seldom drink with him?"
      },
      {
        question:"我很少和他喝酒因为他总是喜欢大声地（loudly）唱歌。",
        answer: "I seldom drink with him because he always likes to sing loudly."
      },
      {
        question:"这些花是给你的.",
        answer: "These flowers are for you."
      },
      {
        question:"这些花是给我的吗？",
        answer: "Are these flowers for me?"
      },
      {
        question:"是的，它们是的",
        answer: "Yes, they are."
      },
      {
        question:"为什么这些花是给我的？",
        answer: "Why are these flowers for me?"
      },
      {
        question:"因为我喜欢你。",
        answer: "Because I like you."
      },
      {
        question:"那本英文书是给我的吗？",
        answer: "Is that English book for me?"
      },
      {
        question:"是的，它是的",
        answer: "Yes, it is."
      },
      {
        question:"为什么那本英文书是给我的？",
        answer: "Why is that English book for me?"
      },
      {
        question:"因为我不想教你英文了。",
        answer: "Because I don't want to teach English for you."
      },
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "40",
    title: "Lesson40 连词if的用法及have to的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question:"为什么我妹妹英语说得非常差？",
        answer: "Why does my sister speak English very badly?"
      },
      {
        question:"她英语说得非常差因为她是非常懒惰的。",
        answer: "She speaks English very badly because she is very lazy."
      },
      {
        question:"如果你妹妹想要说好英语，她必须努力学习。",
        answer: "If your sister wants to speak English well, she have to study hard."
      },
      {
        question:"我想要和杰森在客厅里玩。",
        answer: "I want to play with Jason in the living room."
      },
      {
        question:"如果你想和杰森玩，你现在必须打扫你的卧室。",
        answer: "If you want to play with Jason, you have to clean your bedroom now."
      },
      {
        question:"你教得好吗？",
        answer: "Do you teach well?"
      },
      {
        question:"是的，我教得非常好。",
        answer: "Yes, I teach very well."
      },
      {
        question:"如果你想要学得快，你必须努力学习。",
        answer: "If you want to learn quickly, you have to study hard."
      },
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "41",
    title: "Lesson41 形式主语it的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question:"每天努力学习是好的。",
        answer: "It is good to study hard every day."
      },
      {
        question:"每天喝酒是不好的。",
        answer: "It is bad to drink every day."
      },
      {
        question:"每天抽烟是不好的。",
        answer: "It is bad to smoke every day."
      },
      {
        question:"对于我来说每天去书店是快乐的。",
        answer: "It is happy for me to go to the bookstore every day."
      },
      {
        question:"对你爸爸来说每天看电视是快乐的。",
        answer: "It is happy for your father to watch TV every day."
      },
      {
        question:"对于她来说和杰森游泳是快乐的。",
        answer: "It is happy for her to swim with Jason."
      },
      {
        question:"如果你想学得好，每天努力学习是非常重要的。",
        answer: "If you want to learn well, it is very important to study hard every day."
      },
      {
        question:"如果你想跑得快，每天练习（practice）是非常重要的。",
        answer: "If you want to run quickly, it is very important to practice every day."
      },
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "42",
    title: "Lesson42 常跟时间搭配的介词at/on/in",
    questions: [
      {
        question:"几点了？",
        answer: "What time is it?"
      },
      {
        question:"现在是8点了。",
        answer: "It is eight o'clock now."
      },
      {
        question:"现在是8点了吗？",
        answer: "Is it eight o'clock now?"
      },
      {
        question:"是的，现在是8点了。",
        answer: "Yes, it is eight o'clock now."
      },
      {
        question:"为什么你非常生气？",
        answer: "Why are you very angry?"
      },
      {
        question:"我很生气是因为我的时钟是坏的（broken）。",
        answer: "I am very angry because my clock is broken."
      },
      {
        question:"在9点钟我有一个重要的考试，所以我必须吃快点",
        answer: "I have am important test at nine o'clock, so I have to eat quickly."
      },
      {
        question:"我也必须开得很快如果我想要在9点抵达那里。",
        answer: "I also have to drive quickly if I want to arrive there at nine o'clock."
      },
      {
        question:"何时是玛丽的生日？",
        answer: "When is Mary's birthday?"
      },
      {
        question:"玛丽的生日是在星期六.",
        answer: "Mary's birthday is on Saturday."
      },
      {
        question:"我想要在星期六庆祝(celebrate)玛丽生日。",
        answer: "I want to celebrate Mary's birthday on Saturday."
      },
      {
        question:"对我来说庆祝玛丽的生日是非常重要的.",
        answer: "It is very important for me to celebrate Mary's birthday."
      },
      {
        question:"如果你想要庆祝玛丽的生日，你必须买一个蛋糕。",
        answer: "If you want to celebrate Mary's birthday, you have to buy a cake."
      },
      {
        question:"星期五我想要在那家蛋糕店买一个蛋糕。",
        answer: "I want to buy a cake at that cake store on Friday."
      },
      {
        question:"那家蛋糕店在哪里？",
        answer: "Where is that cake store?"
      },
      {
        question:"那家蛋糕店在书店附近。",
        answer: "That cake store is near the bookstore."
      },
      {
        question:"星期五你想要和我去买个蛋糕吗？",
        answer: "Do you want to buy a cake with me on Friday?"
      },
      {
        question:"虽然星期五我有个重要的考试, 但我想要和你买蛋糕。",
        answer: "Although I have an important test on Friday, I want to buy a cake with you."
      },
      {
        question:"你何时来台湾？",
        answer: "When do you come to Taiwan?"
      },
      {
        question:"我打算在10月份去台湾。",
        answer: "I plan to go to Taiwan in October."
      },
      {
        question:"10月份有许多游客（tourists）在台湾。",
        answer: "There are many tourists in Taiwan in October."
      },
      {
        question:"为什么10月份有许多游客（tourists）在台湾？",
        answer: "Why are there many tourists in Taiwan in October?"
      },
      {
        question:"因为在10月份台湾天气是非常凉爽的。",
        answer: "Because it is very cool in Taiwan in October."
      },
      {
        question:"在7月份台湾也有许多美国人吗？",
        answer: "Are there also many Americans in Taiwan in July?"
      },
      {
        question:"是的，7月份也有许多美国人在台湾。",
        answer: "Yes, there are also many Americans in Taiwan in July."
      },
      {
        question:"我喜欢每天上学。",
        answer: "I like to go to school every day."
      },
      {
        question:"你也喜欢每天上学吗？",
        answer: "Do you also like to go to school every day?"
      },
      {
        question:"不，我讨厌每天上学。",
        answer: "No, I hate to go to school every day."
      },
      {
        question:"因为学校的那只狗总是喜欢咬（bite）我。",
        answer: "Because the dog in the school always likes to bite to me."
      },
      {
        question:"如果你想要和玛丽游泳，今天早上你必须完成这个工作。",
        answer: "If you want to swim with Mary, you have to finish the work this morning."
      },
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "43",
    title: "Lesson43 原级/比较级/最高级的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question:"她像我一样开心。",
        answer: "She is as happy as I."
      },
      {
        question:"为什么她像你一样开心？",
        answer: "Why is she as happy as you?"
      },
      {
        question:"她像我一样开心因为我们今天要去动物园。",
        answer: "She is as happy as I because we want to go to the zoo today."
      },
      {
        question:"为什么你的弟弟像她妹妹一样伤心呢？",
        answer: "Why is your brother as sad as she sister?"
      },
      {
        question:"我弟弟像她妹妹一样伤心因为这个早上他们必须学习英文。",
        answer: "My brother is as sad as her sister because they have to learn English this morning."
      },
      {
        question:"你学英文学得好吗？",
        answer: "Do you learn English well?"
      },
      {
        question:"是的，我学英文学得非常好。",
        answer: "Yes, I learn English very well."
      },
      {
        question:"我英文学得像她一样好。",
        answer: "I learn English as well as she."
      },
      {
        question:"他和你一样聪明吗？",
        answer: "Is he as smart as you?"
      },
      {
        question:"不，他比我聪明。",
        answer: "No, he is smarter than I."
      },
      {
        question:"虽然他比你聪明，你工作比他努力。",
        answer: "Although he is smarter than you, you work harder than he."
      },
      {
        question:"因为我工作比他努力，我比他更富有。",
        answer: "Because I work harder than he, I am richer than he."
      },
      {
        question:"你的女儿比他女儿更漂亮吗？",
        answer: "Is your daughter more beautiful than his daughter?"
      },
      {
        question:"是的，我的女儿比他的女儿更漂亮。",
        answer: "Yes, my daughter is more beautiful than his daughter."
      },
      {
        question:"你比那个医生更快乐吗？",
        answer: "Are you happier than that doctor?"
      },
      {
        question:"是的，我比那个医生更快乐。",
        answer: "Yes, I am happier than that doctor."
      },
      {
        question:"那只狐狸（fox）是森林里跑得最快的。",
        answer: "The fox runs the fastest in the forest."
      },
      {
        question:"为什么那只狐狸（fox）是森林里跑得最快的？",
        answer: "Why does that fox run the fastest in the forest?"
      },
      {
        question:"因为它跑得比那只老虎还快。",
        answer: "Because it runs faster than that tiger."
      },
      {
        question:"这朵花是森林里最漂亮的花。",
        answer: "The flower is the most beautiful in the forest."
      },
      {
        question:"为什么这朵花是森林里最漂亮的？",
        answer: "Why is the flower the most beautiful in the forest?"
      },
      {
        question:"因为这朵花跟你一样漂亮。",
        answer: "Because the flower is as beautiful as you."
      },
      {
        question:"那个农夫是镇上最富有的人。",
        answer: "That farmer is the richest person in the town."
      },
      {
        question:"为什么那个农夫是镇上最富有的人？",
        answer: "Why is that farmer the richest person in the town?"
      },
      {
        question:"因为那个农夫工作跟我一样努力。",
        answer: "Because that farmer works as hard as I."
      },
      {
        question:"这个棒球手是学校里最好的。",
        answer: "The baseball player is the best in the school."
      },
      {
        question:"他也是学校里最高大（biggest）的学生。",
        answer: "He is also the biggest student in the school."
      },
      {
        question:"那个老师是学校里最差（worst）的。",
        answer: "That teacher is the worst in the school."
      },
      {
        question:"你更喜欢游泳吗？",
        answer: "Do you like to swim more?"
      },
      {
        question:"我喜欢游泳多于我喜欢跑步。",
        answer: "I like to swim more than I like to run."
      },
      {
        question:"我最喜欢游泳了。",
        answer: "I like to swim the most."
      },
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "44",
    title: "Lesson44 现在进行时的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question:"你在哪里？",
        answer: "Where are you?"
      },
      {
        question:"我在公园里。",
        answer: "I am in the park."
      },
      {
        question:"我正在公园里散步。",
        answer: "I am walking in the park."
      },
      {
        question:"对我来说每天散步是非常重要的。",
        answer: "It is very important for me to walk every day."
      },
      {
        question:"有许多人现在正在公园里散步。",
        answer: "There are many persons walking in the park now."
      },
      {
        question:"你想要来这里吗？",
        answer: "Do you want to come here?"
      },
      {
        question:"不，我正在客厅里看电视。",
        answer: "No, I am watching TV in the living room."
      },
      {
        question:"我喜欢看电视多于我喜欢散步。",
        answer: "I like to watch TV more than I like to walk."
      },
      {
        question:"你现在正在做什么呢？",
        answer: "What are you doing now?"
      },
      {
        question:"我正在写字。",
        answer: "I am writing."
      },
      {
        question:"为什么你正在写字呢？",
        answer: "Why are you writing?"
      },
      {
        question:"因为我正在做我的作业。",
        answer: "Because I am doing my homework."
      },
      {
        question:"Jason 在哪里？",
        answer: "Where is Jason?"
      },
      {
        question:"他正在和他的狗玩。",
        answer: "He is playing with his dog."
      },
      {
        question:"他们正在挖花园的土（dirt）吗？",
        answer: "Are they digging the dirt in the garden?"
      },
      {
        question:"不，他们正在森林里玩。",
        answer: "No, they are playing in the forest."
      },
      {
        question:"他们正在玩什么？",
        answer: "What are they playing?"
      },
      {
        question:"他们正在跑步。",
        answer: "They are running."
      },
      {
        question:"谁跑得比较快？",
        answer: "Who runs faster?"
      },
      {
        question:"Jason 跑得比那只胖狗快。",
        answer: "Jason runs faster than that fat dog."
      },
      {
        question:"你也跑得像Jason一样快吗？",
        answer: "Do you also run as fast as Jason?"
      },
      {
        question:"不，我跑得像那只胖狗一样慢。",
        answer: "No, I run as slowly as that fat dog."
      },
      {
        question:"你现在在做什么？",
        answer: "What are you doing now?"
      },
      {
        question:"我正在公园里跑步。",
        answer: "I am running in the park."
      },
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "45",
    title: "Lesson45 现在完成时的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question:"我现在非常饿。",
        answer: "I am very hungry now."
      },
      {
        question:"你想要吃一个鸡蛋吗？",
        answer: "Do you want to eat an egg?"
      },
      {
        question:"我已经吃了9个鸡蛋了。",
        answer: "I have eaten nine eggs."
      },
      {
        question:"你想要吃一些面包吗？",
        answer: "Do you want to eat some bread?"
      },
      {
        question:"我已经吃了很多面包了。",
        answer: "I have eaten much bread."
      },
      {
        question:"你想要喝一些果汁吗？",
        answer: "Do you want to drink some juice?"
      },
      {
        question:"我已经喝了许多果汁了。",
        answer: "I have drunk much juice."
      },
      {
        question:"你必须现在去睡觉因为你已经吃了许多东西了。",
        answer: "You have to go sleep now because you have eaten many things."
      },
      {
        question:"你想要买那本最新的小说（novel）吗？",
        answer: "Do you want to buy the newest novel?"
      },
      {
        question:"我已经买了那本最新的小说了。",
        answer: "I have bought that newest novel."
      },
      {
        question:"你已经读了那本小说了吗？",
        answer: "Have you read that novel?"
      },
      {
        question:"不，我还没有读那本小说。",
        answer: "No, I have not read that novel."
      },
      {
        question:"你现在正在做什么？",
        answer: "What are you doing now?"
      },
      {
        question:"我现在正在洗我爸爸的车。",
        answer: "I am washing my dad's car."
      },
      {
        question:"你已经完成了你的作业了吗？",
        answer: "Have you finished your homework?"
      },
      {
        question:"是的，我已经完成了我的作业。",
        answer: "Yes, I have finished my homework."
      },
      {
        question:"我还没完成我的作业因为我正在读那本小说。",
        answer: "I have not finished my homework because I am reading that novel."
      },
      {
        question:"你曾经去过韩国吗？",
        answer: "Have you ever been to Korea?"
      },
      {
        question:"不，我还没去过韩国",
        answer: "No, I have not been to Korea."
      },
      {
        question:"你已经去过哪一个国家呢？",
        answer: "Which country have you been to?"
      },
      {
        question:"我已经去过泰国（Thailand）、日本和美国。",
        answer: "I have been to Thailand, Japan and America."
      },
      {
        question:"今天我弟弟已经去泰国（Thailand）了。",
        answer: "My brother has gone to Thailand today."
      },
      {
        question:"他喜欢泰国(Thailand)因为那里有许多好吃的海鲜。",
        answer: "He likes Thailand because There is much delicious seafood there."
      },
      {
        question:"我计划这个月去英国。",
        answer: "I plan to go to England this month."
      },
      {
        question:"你曾经去过英国吗？",
        answer: "Have you ever been to England?"
      },
      {
        question:"是的，我已经去过英国了。",
        answer: "Yes, I have been to England."
      },
      {
        question:"我喜欢英国，因为英国是一个漂亮的国家。",
        answer: "I like England because England is a beautiful country."
      },
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "46",
    title: "Lesson46 现在完成进行时的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question:"他已经洗完车了吗?",
        answer: "Has he washed the car?"
      },
      {
        question:"不，他还没有洗完车。",
        answer: "No, he has not washed the car."
      },
      {
        question:"他已经持续洗车2小时了。",
        answer: "He has been washing the car for two hours."
      },
      {
        question:"为什么他已经持续洗车2小时了?",
        answer: "Why has he been washing the car for two hours?"
      },
      {
        question:"他已经持续洗车2小时因为那辆车非常脏。",
        answer: "He has been washing the car for two hours because that car is very dirty."
      },
      {
        question:"你的女儿正在哭吗?",
        answer: "Is your daughter crying?"
      },
      {
        question:"是的，她已经持续哭40分钟了。",
        answer: "Yes, she has been crying for forty minutes."
      },
      {
        question:"为什么她已经持续哭40分钟呢？",
        answer: "Why has she been crying for forty minutes?"
      },
      {
        question:"因为她还没有完成她的作业。",
        answer: "Because she has not finished her homework."
      },
      {
        question:"他已经完成了他的作业了吗？",
        answer: "Has he finished his homework?"
      },
      {
        question:"不，他还没完成他的作业。",
        answer: "No, he has not finished his homework."
      },
      {
        question:"从3点开始他就已经持续地睡觉。",
        answer: "He has been sleeping since three o'clock."
      },
      {
        question:"他已经持续睡了4小时了。",
        answer: "He has been sleeping for four hours."
      },
      {
        question:"为什么从3点开始他就已经持续地睡觉？",
        answer: "Why has he been sleeping since three o'clock?"
      },
      {
        question:"因为他今天非常累。",
        answer: "Because he is very tired today."
      },
      {
        question:"今天下午他已经持续走了1小时。",
        answer: "He has been walking for one hour this afternoon."
      },
      {
        question:"为什么今天下午他已经持续走了1小时？",
        answer: "Why has he been walking for one hour this afternoon?"
      },
      {
        question:"因为他的自行车坏了。",
        answer: "Because his bicycle is broken."
      },
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "47",
    title: "Lesson47 一般过去时的用法",
    questions: [
      {
        question:"我以前是一位医生。",
        answer: "I was a doctor before."
      },
      {
        question:"你以前是一位医生吗？",
        answer: "Were you a doctor before?"
      },
      {
        question:"是的，我以前是一位医生。",
        answer: "Yes, I was a doctor before."
      },
      {
        question:"因为我喜欢教英文，我现在是一位英文老师。",
        answer: "Because I like to teach English, I am a English teacher now."
      },
      {
        question:"你何时在这个城市里教英文呢？",
        answer: "When did you teach English in this city?"
      },
      {
        question:"去年我开始在这个城市里教英文。",
        answer: "I started to teach English in the city last year."
      },
      {
        question:"你以前在哪里教英文？",
        answer: "Where did you teach English before?"
      },
      {
        question:"我两年之前在台北（Taipei）教英语。",
        answer: "I taught English in Taipei tow years ago."
      },
      {
        question:"台北（Taipei）也是一个漂亮的城市。",
        answer: "Taipei is also a beautiful city."
      },
    ]
  },
  {
    lessonId: "48",
    title: "Lesson48 过去进行时的用法",
    questions: []
  },
  {
    lessonId: "49",
    title: "Lesson49 过去完成时的用法",
    questions: []
  },
  {
    lessonId: "50",
    title: "Lesson50 过去完成进行时的用法",
    questions: []
  },
  {
    lessonId: "51",
    title: "Lesson51 一般将来时的用法",
    questions: []
  },
  {
    lessonId: "52",
    title: "Lesson52 将来进行时的用法",
    questions: []
  },
  {
    lessonId: "53",
    title: "Lesson53 将来完成时的用法",
    questions: []
  },
  {
    lessonId: "54",
    title: "Lesson54 将来完成进行时的用法",
    questions: []
  },
  {
    lessonId: "55",
    title: "Lesson55 常用情态动词can/may/must",
    questions: []
  },
  {
    lessonId: "56",
    title: "Lesson56 与现在事实相反的虚拟语气",
    questions: []
  },
  {
    lessonId: "57",
    title: "Lesson57 被动语态",
    questions: []
  },
  {
    lessonId: "58",
    title: "Lesson58 关系代词的用法",
    questions: []
  },
  {
    lessonId: "59",
    title: "Lesson59 动名词的用法",
    questions: []
  }
];
